Irwin Casper Collection of Brush Product Literature
Irwin Casper Collection of Brush Product Literature
1959-1994
Casper, Irwin.
1 linear ft.
Collection contains catalogs and product literature on various brands of hair brushes, combs, toothbrushes, household brushes, and industrial brushes from American and international companies.
2651114
Biographical History
Unknown.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Irwin Casper Collection of Brush Product Literature contains product literature on various brands of hair brushes, toothbrushes, household brushes, and industrial brushes from American and international companies.
Arrangement of the Collection
Boxes are arranged alphabetically by company.
Related Material
has numerous holdings in the areas of plastics and industrial design. Please refer to for a complete listing. The Plastics Artifacts Collection contains many examples.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Plastics; Plastics industry and trade.; Brooms and brushes.; Toothbrushes.; Hair -- Care and hygiene.; Brochures.; Promotional materials.; Advertisements.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from National Plastics Center and Museum, 11/06/2008. Originally, gift of Irwin Casper.
Inventory
- Printed material
  - Catalogs, Product literature on various brands of hair brushes, combs, toothbrushes, household brushes, and industrial brushes from American and international companies
    - All-American Brush Mfg. Corp. (Box 1)
      1 Catalog of promotional information and materials
      1 Planning book of product information
    - Artex (Box 1)
      1 Catalog
    - Beecham Products USA, 1988 (Box 1)
      1 Aquafresh "results" pamphlet
    - Bennington Brush Company (Box 1)
      2 Catalogs of product information
      16 Assorted 8x10 product photographs
      3 Assorted product information sheets
    - Big Eagle Company Ltd. (Box 1)
      1 Paper with company contact information
    - Celluloid s.a., 1992-1993 (Box 1)
      1 Catalog titled "Nouveautes"
      1 Product index
      1 Product catalog
      1 Letter from F. Caron
    - Colgate Oral Pharmaceuticals, 1994 (Box 1)
      1 Informational pamphlet
    - Condor (Box 1)
      2 General catalogs
      1 Letter from Ulisses Godoy
    - Coronet, 1977-1982 (Box 1)
      1 Catalog titled "the attractive range"
      1 Packet of product and sales information
      1 Book "The Successful Coronet Programme"
    - Derby, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
      2 Catalogs
    - E. I. du Pont Nemours and Company (Box 1)
      1 Catalog titled "quality toiletries for the whole family"
    - Ebser (Box 1)
      1 Document describing manufacturing equipment
    - Empire Brushes Inc. (Box 1)
      1 Advertisement
    - F&F Founders Enterprises Ltd., 1979 (Box 1)
      1 Offer sheet and invoice
    - First Co. Plastic Fty. (Box 1)
      1 Product sheet with price list
    - Flamingo, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Foster Grant Co. Inc., 1967 (Box 1)
      1 Price list for nylon combs
      2 Promotional pages for unbreakable nylon combs
      1 Memo to all wholesale salesmen
    - Gaylord Products (Box 1)
    - Gibson-Thomsen Co. Inc. (Box 1)
    - Golden Uly Int'l Co. Ltd., 1984 (Box 1)
      1 Price list with product images
    - Goody, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Grand Fuhsing Co. Ltd. (Box 1)
      1 Packet of product images
    - Hamivreshet Ruhama, 1984 (Box 1)
      2 Catalogs for Ruhama brushes
    - Jackson Associate Corp., 1983 (Box 1)
      1 Catalog with attached letter from Jackson Huang
    - John O. Butler Company, 1989-1994 (Box 2)
      1 Catalog "the butler smile factory"
      2 Product catalogs
      1 Sales catalog
      1 Sales pamphlet
    - Johnson & Johnson, 1994 (Box 2)
      1 Professional products pamphlet
    - Kent of London, 1959 (Box 2)
      1 Catalog with attached letter from Eric L.H. Cosby Jr.
    - Life-Time Merchandising, 1966 (Box 2)
      1 Sales catalog with attached memo
    - Lyon Enterprise Co. Ltd. (Box 2)
    - Marvel Sales Co. Inc., 1967 (Box 2)
      1 Price list with promotional page
    - Monofil (Box 2)
      1 Catalog with price list
    - Oral-B, 1987-1992 (Box 2)
      1 Pamphlet for the "ultra toothbrush"
      1 Advertisement for the "ultra toothbrush"
      1 Pamphlet for "snap lock interdental brush system"
      1 Sales packet with price list
    - Pai-Ta Brush Co. Ltd., 1983 (Box 2)
      1 Price list with product images and attached letter from Jackson Liu
    - Piace Companhia Industrial (Box 2)
      11 Assorted pages of product images
      1 Export price list
      1 Paper with company address
    - Paul A. Price Co. Inc., 1967 (Box 2)
      1 Catalog with attached letter from Louis G. Katz
    - Pioneer Hair Care Products Limited, 1986 (Box 2)
    - The PK Group (Box 2)
      1 Product list
    - Radius (Box 2)
    - Sears (Box 2)
      1 Page image of comb display
    - Sekine, 1962-1980 (Box 2)
      1 Catalog of professional styling brushes
      1 Catalog of "style and groom" brushes
      6 Assorted pages of product information
    - Solo, 1967-1969 (Box 2)
      1 Catalog with wholesale price list
    - Spa, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Stanley Comb Products Corp., 1967 (Box 2)
      1 Distributor price list with product catalog
    - Sterkel, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Sunbeam (Box 2)
      1 Informational pamphlet with attached presentation abstract
    - Sup-Erb Brush Company, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Tai Max International Co. Ltd., 1987 (Box 2)
      1 Page with product photographs
    - Tigre (Box 2)
      1 Catalog of artist brushes and accessories
      1 Catalog of paint brushes, paint rollers, and accessories
      1 Letter from Dr. Jader Fernades S. Borges
    - Tilton & Cook Co., 1979 (Box 2)
    - Tin Ngai Industrial Co. Ltd. (Box 2)
      1 Price list with attached photograph
    - Tip-Top, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Tung Fat Plastic Co., 1982 (Box 2)
    - Wah Hing Plastic and Metalware Fty. Ltd., 1983 (Box 2)
    - Welgroom (Box 2)
    - Wisdom Toothbrush Company, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Worldwide Dental, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Yung Hsang Development Co. Ltd. (Box 2)
      1 Paper with attached product photographs
  - Periodicals
    - Brushwork, January 1988 (Box 2)
      Vol. 1 Number 1
    - Packaging Digest, 1986-1989 (Box 2)
      Vol. 23 Number 7
      Vol. 26 Number 6